Guide to the Interfraternity Council records, 1947-2001 UA.31.19.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Interfraternity Council records
1947-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Interfraternity Council
UA.31.19.0001
3 Linear Feet
The Interfraternity Council at Duke University, established in 1957, is the umbrella organization for local chapters of national fraternities. The Council interacts with representatives of campus fraternities to promote adherence to University policies and to create opportunities for fraternities to serve the campus community. This collection contains meeting agendas and minutes, pledge programs, certificates, manuals, clippings, incident reports, reports, miscellaneous writings, and printed material. General topics include correspondence between fraternities and the Interfraternity Council, judicial board files, individual chapter constitutions and bylaws, alcohol policies, hazing, pledging, property damage to fraternity houses, leadership, scholarship, and reorganization of fraternities at Duke. Contains restricted materials. The bulk of material is from 1960-1980. English.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
Transfer; 1975; 75-68.
Transfer; 1978; 78-133
Transfer; 1980; 80-11.
Transfer; 1989; A89-0020.
Transfer; 1998; A98-7.
Historical Note
The Interfraternity Council at Duke University, established in 1957, is the umbrella organization for Duke University chapters of national fraternities. The Interfraternity Council primarily interacts with the Council of Presidents (presidents of campus fraternities) to promote adherence to University policies and to create leadership opportunities for fraternities to serve the campus community. The Interfraternity Council is divided into legislative, executive and judicial branches.
The Legislative Board is called the Council of Presidents and includes the presidents of all member fraternities. The Council of Presidents convenes to vote on administrative matters of the Interfraternity Council.
The Executive Council generally facilitates policy creation and assembles committees to work on special events and community service projects. Over the years, these activities have consisted of Greek Week, Shoe and Slipper Weekend, Help Week, and many outdoor concerts. The Executive Council also handles record keeping, publications, and financial accounting.
The Judicial Board enforces the Interfraternity Council Penal Code, tries cases involving infractions by member fraternities, and levies appropriate punishment. Fraternities must maintain good standing with the Council by paying dues, providing periodic financial reports, and completing service projects. Some of the issues reported to the Judicial Board are noise and alcohol violations, hazing, pledging rules, and property damage to fraternity houses.
The Interfraternity Council generally supports fraternity presence at Duke University by employing outside contractors and advisory boards. The input from these sources has helped fraternities make policy decisions about going co-ed, closing a chapter, or updating their image. Since 1954, the Interfraternity Council has published many handbooks for students including: The Greek Way (1954-2001), Rushing Relations (1969-1970), and Open Relations (1961-1969).
Collection Overview
The Interfraternity Council at Duke University, established in 1957, is the umbrella organization for Duke University chapters of national fraternities. The Interfraternity Council primarily interacts with the Council of Presidents (presidents of campus fraternities) to promote adherence to University policies and to create leadership opportunities for fraternities to serve the campus community. This collection contains meeting agenda and minutes, pledge programs, certificates, manuals, chapter constitutions and bylaws, incident reports, and printed material related to the Interfraternity Council's governance over fraternities at Duke University. Materials range in date from 1947-2001
Related Material
Fraternities and Sororities collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
Panhellenic Council records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Baldwin, Steven L. and Susan Coon Final Report. Office of Student Affairs. Task Force on Greek Life, 1994. Call number: 378.1985 D877 F491 1994
Duke University. Interfraternity Council Fraternity Life at Duke, [1947-1975] Call number: 371.855 D877F
Downhower, Laura Spring Sorority Rush: a Booklet for First-year Women about Rush and Sororities at Duke, 1989 Call number: 378.19856 S769 1989
Duke University. Woman's Panhellenic Council. Sororities at Duke: a Booklet to Tell You the Whys and Hows of Rushing, [1953-1968] Call number: 371.856 D877G
Initiations (into trades, societies, etc.); Hazing; Male college students; College students -- Alcohol use -- North Carolina -- Durham; Greek letter societies -- North Carolina -- Durham; Greek letter societies; Duke University. Interfraternity Council; Duke University -- Students -- Social conditions; Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc.; Duke University -- Interfraternity Council; Duke University -- Societies, etc.
- Minutes and Agendas, 1961-1995.
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains minutes and agendas from Board of Advisors, and Council of Presidents and Executive Board meetings.
  Arrangement note
  Ordered alphabetically.
  - Minutes, Board of Advisors Meeting, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Agendas, IFC Presidents Meetings, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Handouts at IFC Presidents Meetings, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
  - Meetings, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, Executive Board, 1961-1964 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, Executive Board, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, IFC Presidents Meetings, 1961-1962
    - 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - 1964-1966 (incomplete for 1965-66) (Box 1)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 1)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 1)
    - 1969-1971 (Box 1)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - 1995 (Box 1)
- Judicial Board Files, 1960-1995.
  Contains incident reports, correspondence, and appeals relating to investigations of misconduct by fraternities.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Judicial Board Files are RESTRICTED.
  - Alpha Phi Alpha, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Alpha Tau Omega, 1960-1981 (Box 1)
  - Beta Phi Zeta, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Beta Theta Pi, undated (Box 1)
  - Delta Sigma Phi, 1967-1983 (Box 1)
  - Delta Tau Delta, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Kappa Alpha, 1960-1967 (Box 1)
  - Kappa Sigma, 1960-1977 (Box 1)
  - Lambda Chi Alpha, 1961-1972 (Box 1)
  - Omega Psi Phi, 1979-1981 (Box 1)
  - Phi Delta Theta, 1960-1983 (Box 1)
  - Phi Kappa Psi, 1960-1981 (Box 1)
  - Phi Kappa Sigma, 1960-1988 (Box 1)
  - Pi Kappa Alpha, 1960-1971 (Box 1)
  - Pi Kappa Phi, 1960-1967 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Alpha Epsilon, 1961-1983 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Chi, 1960-1980 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Nu, 1960-1995 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Phi Epsilon, 1977-1993 (Box 1)
  - Tau Epsilon Phi, 1973-1980 (Box 1)
  - Theta Chi, 1963-1982 (Box 1)
  - Zeta Beta Tau, 1962-1968 (Box 1)
- Fraternity Constitutions and Bylaws, 1971-1978.
  Contains constitutions, bylaws, and miscellaneous notes on chapter establishment of fraternities.
  - Beta Phi Zeta-Constitution and Bylaws, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Kappa Alpha, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Kappa Alpha Psi-Bylaws, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Kappa Sigma, Bylaws, undated (Box 1)
  - Omega Psi Phi-Chapter Establishment, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Phi Kappa Sigma, Bylaws, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Psi Upsilon, Bylaws, undated (Box 1)
  - Sigma Alpha Epsilon, Bylaws, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Nu, Bylaws, undated (Box 1)
  - Sigma Phi Epsilon, Constitution, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Tau Epsilon Phi-Bylaws, undated (Box 1)
  - Theta Chi-Bylaws, 1976 (Box 1)
- General Subject files, 1957-2000, bulk 1970-1995.
  Contains general materials about grades, pledging, housing, rush, leadership, and scholarship of fraternities at Duke University. Ordered alphabetically by subject. Contains restricted materials.
  - AIH Presidents, Residential Staff, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol Policy, 1994-1997 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol Policy, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Annual Review Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Attendance Policy, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Bylaws, revised, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Campus Affairs (Community Service), 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Candidates for officers, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
    Candidates for officers materials are RESTRICTED.
  - Certificates, 1957, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Clean-up Policy, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Committee Descriptions, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Committee Interviews, 1971 (Box 1)
    Committee Interviews materials are RESTRICTED.
  - Committees, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Committees, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Constitution, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Constitution, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1989, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Damage Policy, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Discriminatory Clauses, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Elections, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Executive Council, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Faculty Associates Program, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Fraternity composites (correspondence with Vantine Studios) (Box 1)
  - Fraternity grade point average summaries, 1966-1989 (Box 1)
  - Fraternity Information Sheets, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Freshman Week, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - History of Fraternity Locations on West Campus Since 1950, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Housing Statistics, 1975-1989 (Box 2)
  - Interfraternity Council Scholarship, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Jewish/Greek Task Force, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Leadership and Service, 1995 (Box 2)
  - List of Campus leaders, officers, organizations, 1962-1963 (Box 2)
  - Living Group Damages, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
  - Membership Records Policy, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
  - General materials, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence, agendas, memoranda, alcohol policy draft, fundraising, position papers by students
  - Newspaper Articles, 1977-1979 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1992-1995 (Box 2)
  - Noise Policy, 1980-1993 (Box 2)
  - North Carolina National Bank, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Panhellenic Council, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Penal Code, Revised, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Petitions and Correspondence regarding move of IFC office, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Picnic, Parents' Weekend, undated (Box 2)
  - Pledge Programs, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Pledge Rules, 1963-1965 (Box 2)
  - Psi Upsilon-Shift to Co-ed Status, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Proposal for Creation of IFC Board of Overseers, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Public Relations, 1980-1989 (Box 2)
  - Requirements for the Establishment of a Fraternity or Sorority at Duke, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Residential Life
    - Correspondence, 1981-1987 (Box 2)
    - IFC Report on Residential Life at Duke Univ., undated (Box 2)
    - Off-Campus Lodges, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Reports and Proposals, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
    - Reports and Proposals, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
    - Reports and Proposals, 1984-1995 (Box 2)
  - Rush and Pledging, 1963-1970, 1994-1997 (Box 2)
  - Rush and Dirty-Rush Rules, 1995 (Box 2)
  - John F. Sacha Current Business, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - John F. Sacha, IFC General and Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
  - Sales Permits; Exchange of Funds, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Southeastern Interfraternity Conference, 1974 -1975 (Box 2)
  - West Campus Community Council, 1965-1969 (Box 2)
- Printed Materials, 1954-2001.
  - Campus Plans with housing locations, 1957-1993 (Box 2)
  - The Greek Way, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - The Greek Way, 1961-1962, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - The Greek Way, 1970-1979 (Box 2)
  - The Greek Way, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - The Greek Way, 1991-1993 (Box 2)
  - The Greek Way, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
  - The Greek Way, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Open Relations, 1961-1962, 1967-1969 (Box 2)
  - Rush Relations, 1969-1970 (Box 2)